[
  {
    "type": "instructions",
    "note": "In each of the following sentences, there is a word underlined and one gap. From the list of word, lettered A to D, choose the word that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the underlined word and that will, at the same time. correctly fill the gap in the sentence."
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "1",
    "question": "Honest labour can lift one from circumstances of <u>poverty</u> to ",
    "answer": "D",
    "options": {
      "A": "happiness. ",
      "B": "generosity. ",
      "C": "development. ",
      "D": "affluence. "
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "2",
    "question": "<u>Trained</u> physicians are more careful than ......... doctors when treating patients.",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "careless ",
      "B": "quack ",
      "C": "reckless ",
      "D": "indifferent "
    }
  },{
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "3",
    "question": "The leader <u>encouraged</u> all present not to be ......... by recent happenings",
    "answer": "B",
    "options": {
      "A": "controlled ",
      "B": "disheartened ",
      "C": "cautioned ",
      "D": "surprised "
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "4",
    "question": "His knowledge in the sciences is only <u>superficial</u> and not ........ . ",
    "answer": "B",
    "options": {
      "A": " profound",
      "B": "instructive. ",
      "C": "complex",
      "D": "strong"
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "5",
    "question": "Electricity supply is only <u>erratic</u> in the city but ....... in the villages.",
    "answer": "B",
    "options": {
      "A": "frequent",
      "B": "stable",
      "C": "normal",
      "D": "available"
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "6",
    "question": "People who talk about others can only do <u>temporary</u>, not ......... damage to them",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "heavy ",
      "B": "serious",
      "C": "lasting",
      "D": "considerable"
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "7",
    "question": " It is difficult to afford <u>sumptuous</u> meals nowadays; one has to make do with ....... ones.",
    "answer": "A",
    "options": {
      "A": "frugal ",
      "B": "unbalanced ",
      "C": "unpalatable ",
      "D": "available "
    }
  },{
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "8",
    "question": "The advantages of <u>reconciliation</u> far outweigh living in ",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "dishamony.",
      "B": "opposition.",
      "C": "indifference.",
      "D": "violence."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "9",
    "question": "Academic performance, which was at its lowest <u>ebb</u>. is now at its",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "climax.",
      "B": "tip.",
      "C": "peak.",
      "D": "maximum."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "10",
    "question": "It is advisable to avoid <u>apathy</u> and embrace",
    "answer": "A",
    "options": {
      "A": "bravery.",
      "B": "leniency.",
      "C": "satisfaction.",
      "D": "enthusiasm."
    }
  }
]
